翻译   国士章鱼X
翻译   小饭
翻译   肉松富士
翻译   某羽
翻译   杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译   艾瑞卡
翻译   somehacker
翻译   面条打包子
时间轴   Kallen
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
鸣谢   忙成狗的网飞
鸣谢   阿小小海
特效   草草
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第三季  第五集
美国国土安全部
联邦应急管理署
联邦应急管理署署长
阿诺德·希尔瓦
希瑟·邓巴  民主党总统候选人
迈克尔·帕斯特纳克
同性恋权利活动家迈克尔·科里根的丈夫
华尔街电讯报
联邦应急管理署遭劫
民众付出代价
总统解雇国防部长
雷米·丹顿  白宫幕僚长
美国在招工
《斯塔福德法案》第一条
"Title One of the Stafford Act:
"紧急情况"是指由总统指定的
'Emergency' means any occasion or instance for which,
场合或情形...
in the determination of the president..."
指定权在总统
"Determined" by the president.
-有先例吗  -只要我们能说明这些措施
- Any instance? - As long as we can make the argument
能拯救生命  保护人民安康就行
that this saves lives and protects health and safety.
失业导致犯罪
Well, unemployment leads to crime,
营养不良  以及恶劣的医疗服务
to malnutrition, to improper medical care.
这种说法肯定会在法庭上遭到攻击的
There's no doubt it'll be challenged in the courts.
就算最终闹上了法庭
Well, even so, by the time that happens,
那时人们也会见识到《美国就业法案》了
people will see what America Works looks like.
告诉我  从法律的角度说
Tell me, in your legal opinion...
你们觉得有足够的回旋余地吗
is there enough leeway here?
有的  法案用词足够模糊
Yes, the language is sufficiently vague.
不过得说清楚  这么做实在是前所未有
But just to be clear, this is completely unorthodox.
从没有哪个总统试过这么筹集资金
No president has ever tried to reappropriate funds this way.
谢谢各位  有这话就够了
Thank you, gentlemen, that's all I need.
各州不会支持的  太激进了
The states won't go for this. Too radical.
哪怕有一个我联系的州长
And if I call just one governor
拒绝了我然后向媒体泄露了风声
who says no and leaks it to the press,
还没等我正式提出  就会被国会穷追猛打
Congress will be on my ass before I get this out of the gates.
但是  哥伦比亚特区
But, the District of Columbia...
-没有州长  -只有你  一个市长
- No governor. - Just you, the mayor.
巴尼  我知道这会让你冒很大风险
Now, Barney, I know this puts you out on a ledge.
我喜欢  每个条款我都支持
I love it. I love everything about it.
我们年年都要为预算的每一分钱跟国会争
We have to fight Congress for every dollar in our budget, each year.
如果选民看到我从他们嘴里抠出钱来
If my people see me take the money they won't give us...
我就能赢得连任
well, I just won reelection.
这就是让巴尼·豪尔这样的强人当选的原因
This is why you put a brawler like Barney Hull in office,
不只是还他人情
aside from paying a debt.
把全美50位州长和535位国会议员加起来
Add up 50 governors and 535 members of Congress,
也赶不上一位有进取心的大胆市长
you don't come close to the gumption of one bold mayor.
我希望全城各处的人都去注册找工作
I want people registering for jobs in every part of the city
越快越好  趁法院还没发难
as soon as possible, before the court challenges bubble up.
在国会门口支个大帐篷怎么样
What about one big tent right in front of the Capitol?
让国会看看民众
Make Congress see the people
排队找工作排到林肯纪念堂的场面
line up all the way back to the Lincoln Memorial.
能在国庆日出手吗
Can we do something by July Fourth?
你只管放烟花  我找人来捧场
You bring the fireworks, I'll bring the people.
早上好  请坐
Good morning. Please, sit.
我知道雷米已经向各位介绍过情况了
I know Remy has just briefed you all,
那么除了国土安全部部长
so, aside from the Secretary of Homeland Security,
已经离职之外  还有谁持反对意见吗
who is no longer with us, does anyone else object to this plan?
很好  在新国安部长上任之前
Good. Until a new secretary is confirmed,
联邦应急管理署将直接对我负责  谢谢各位
FEMA will report directly to me. Thank you all very much.
失业不能
Unemployment doesn't
算作是自然灾害  总统先生
constitute a natural disaster, Mr. President.
《斯塔福德法案》授权我
The Stafford Act gives me full authority
定义紧急状况
to define an emergency.
但是  先生  我们的赈灾基金
But, sir, we've only got about three billion left
只剩下30亿不到了
in the Disaster Relief Fund,
而飓风季眼看就要来了
and we're about to go into hurricane season.
我们先用这现成的30亿
So we use the three billion that's there,
万一飓风来袭了
and if a hurricane hits,
国会定会拨款补充赈灾基金  他们一向如此
Congress replenishes the funds, just as they always do.
灾害发生后  每分每秒都极其珍贵  先生
When it comes to a disaster, every hour counts, sir.
如果还得等国会那边
If we're waiting around for Congress--
希尔瓦先生  这事就这么定了
Mr. Silva, this is moving forward.
平民会死伤惨重的  总统先生
People could die, Mr. President.
平民要是没工作  也会活不成的
People are dying because they don't have jobs.
虽然比死于地震洪水慢  但一样是死
Slower than a flood or an earthquake, but dying just the same.
您怎么能拿失业和4级飓风相提并论
You can't compare unemployment to a cat four hurricane.
我来你办公室找你
I came to your office
是希望你能继续坐在这个位子上
because I want this to remain your office.
连续三任总统都让你留任不是平白无故
There's a reason three presidents have kept you here.
你专心致志  坚持不懈
You're dedicated, you're relentless,
而且工作能力极为优秀
you're exceptionally competent.
如果我们需要精打细算
If we have to stretch dollars even further,
找你准没错
you're the man to do it.
如果你走人了  就得找个没经验的了
It's either you or someone far less experienced.
两位周末就要去爱荷华了
The two of you head to Iowa at the end of the week.
是的  这一趟要去18个郡拉票
That's right. Eighteen counties this trip.
希望一月之前能走遍全州99个郡
By January, I plan on hitting all 99.
约翰会和我一起出席活动  直到他丈夫获释
John will join me at every event until his husband is released.
自从迈克尔被捕后你和他联系过吗
Have you had any contact with Michael since his arrest?
俄罗斯政府拒绝了
The Russian government has refused.
他们甚至不让他见律师
They won't let him speak to a lawyer.
所以约翰和我站在一起意义重大
That's why it's important John join me.
我们必须对莫斯科持续施压
We need to keep the pressure up on Moscow.
在全国许多地方  同性恋权益
You know, gay rights is controversial
都是极具争议性的话题
in many parts of the country.
您不担心和科里根的丈夫站在一起
Do you think that appearing with Corrigan's husband
会对您的选情不利吗
could possibly hurt you?
我认为美国人民想要一位不逃避问题的候选人
I think the American people want a candidate who doesn't dodge,
会诚实表达自己的立场
who is truthful about where she stands.
而不是回避争议
Not someone who shies away from controversy.
回避争论是一回事
It's one thing to shy away from controversy.
引发争论是另一回事
It's another thing to court it.
迈克尔因为直抒己见被捕
Well, Michael was arrested for speaking his mind.
如果捍卫言论自由有争议  那么...
If defending free speech is controversial, then...
我们不比俄罗斯好多少
we're no better than Russia.
真希望我们的政府里
I wish that there were
有更多人去捍卫言论自由
more people in our government defending it.
你指的是安德伍德政府吗
Are you talking specifically about the Underwood Administration?
我认为总统可以采取更多措施
I think the president could do more.
白宫表示他们已经直接与
You know, the White House has said hat they've been speaking
克里姆林宫方面沟通  他们原话是
directly with the Kremlin, that they, and I quote here:
"必须解决这一问题  因为这关系到
"Have to tackle this issue as it relates to the larger
两国之间更重要的外交关系"
diplomatic relationship between the two nations."
那我们为什么还没看到这些对话的证据呢
Then why haven't we seen any evidence of those talks?
我当选总统后  美国人民可以放心
When I'm president, the American people can rest assured
我会认真履行
that I will take my oath
捍卫和保护我们人民的誓言
to defend and protect our citizens seriously.
-你觉得她怎么样  -什么  邓巴吗
- What do you think of her? - What, Dunbar?
对
Yeah.
我认为这届政府做得还不够好
I believe that the administration could do better...
-你为安德伍德工作过  -现在不了
- You worked for Underwood. - Not anymore.
我不会生气的
I won't be offended.
我很喜欢她说的这些
Uh, I like a lot about what she has to say.
你会投票给她吗
Would you vote for her?
不知道  可能吧
I don't know. I might.
是啊  很可能会
Yeah. Probably would.
-多快  -明天
- How soon? - Tomorrow.
我们会在这事上遭强烈抨击
We're gonna get hit hard on this.
总好过因为科里根的事被抨击
Better than getting hit on Corrigan.
你看《维埃拉秀》了吗
You saw Vieira?
邓巴很聪明
Dunbar's smart.
我们还没参选她就开始打压我们
She's running against us before we're even running.
她也会在联邦应急管理署这事上攻击我们
She'll attack us on the FEMA thing, too.
那就让她攻击  至少是我们控制舆论
Then let her. At least we're controlling the narrative.
我们第一次谈时  你说初秋
When we first spoke, you mentioned early fall.
听着  邓巴势头强盛是因为没人挑战她
Look, Dunbar's got momentum because no one's challenging her.
但我们一宣布联邦应急管理署的计划
But once we drop the FEMA plan,
就会盖过她的报道
that'll take her off message.
然后你宣布参选就会分散她的注意  连环出击
And your candidacy will distract her. It's a one-two punch.
我们会开始抢走女性选民的选票
We'll start bleeding away the woman's vote.
我不确定现在几乎毫无准备
I'm just not sure how smart it is to rush into a campaign
-就宣布参选是否有利  -又不是真的参选
- with so little preparation. - This isn't a real campaign.
但要看起来像真格的
But it needs to look like one.
我以为你想跟我一队呢
I thought you wanted to be on my ticket.
我要赌上声誉
It's my reputation at stake.
-我不想看起来有勇无谋  -听着  没人...
- I don't want to look foolhardy. - Look, no one--
市长明早将会宣布
Mayor's announcing in the morning.
赛斯在跟他办公室合作
Seth's working with his office.
你看  杰姬  现在是最佳时机
You see, Jackie, this is perfect timing.
联邦应急管理署计划开始实施
The FEMA plan goes into action,
你几周后宣布参选  说你必须参选
you announce in a couple of weeks, you say you had to run.
安德伍德总统在联邦应急管理署恣意妄为
President Underwood is being reckless with FEMA.
你出面反对我
You come out against me
和《美国就业法案》  然后抢了邓巴的风头
and America Works and you steal Dunbar's thunder.
之后等到我退出
And then I flip-flop
与你一同参选  不是态度大转弯吗
when I pull out and you put me on the ticket?
到那时候  五万人将拥有工作
By then, 50,000 people will have jobs,
那就不像是态度大转弯了
and it won't look like a flip-flop.
而是你豁然开朗
It'll look like you saw the light.
听着  你跟雷米一起出去
Now, look, why don't you go off with Remy
讨论一下细节
and you discuss the details,
多考虑考虑再做决定
and just give it some thought before you decide.
-谢谢  总统先生  -来我办公室谈吧
- Thank you, Mr. President. - Let's talk in my office.
我最大的担心是资金
My biggest concern is funding.
我总不能坐普通舱去爱荷华
I couldn't fly coach to Iowa.
我给你找一笔政治行动委员会资金来铺路
I'll get you some PAC money rolling your way.
应该足以让你启动宣传了
Should be enough to get you started.
如果我参选  就不能虎头蛇尾
If I run, it shouldn't be half-ass.
所以我们得好好谈谈这个
Which is why we should talk about this.
你想要有完整家庭的候选人
You want a candidate with a family.
我们要抢的就是女性选民的选票
We are after the woman's vote.
艾伦和我已经讨论过了
Alan and I have already talked about it.
是吗
You have?
对  我们第一次约会时就开过结婚的玩笑
Yeah. We joked about getting married on our first date.
我不用生产就能有两个孩子
I get two kids without the stretch marks.
当我提到可能参选时  这就不再是玩笑话了
And when I mentioned I might run, it stopped becoming a joke.
艾伦能接受吗
Is Alan open to it?
-本就是他的主意  -那你呢
- It was his idea. - And what about you?
我们深爱彼此
We do love each other.
他看上去是个好人
He seems like a good guy.
是的  他的孩子也很棒
He is. And his children are wonderful.
你也应该考虑结婚
You should think about getting hitched.
我们要谈谈时间表吗
Should we talk timeline?
-结婚的吗  -竞选
- For marriage? - The campaign.
这可不是提议  这是会谈
This is far from an offer. This is a conversation.
而且是个从没发生过的会谈
And it's a conversation that never happened.
我从后门进来  待会儿还从后门离开
I took the back door in, I'll take the back door out.
本季度工资单上没有你
We keep you off the payroll this quarter.
你9月30日正式开始任职
You start officially September 30th.
下个季度的选举委员会文件才会有我  可以
Next quarter's FEC filings. It's fine.
关于工资你有什么想法
What are you thinking in terms of salary?
每季度2.2万
Twenty-two thousand per quarter.
就算我这样  也不只值这个价
That's way below what I'm worth. Even in this state.
你觉得多少合适
What do you think's appropriate?
25万加上3%的广告投入
Two-fifty and three points on the ad-buy.
-我们负担不起  -不  你们担得起
- That's beyond our means. - No, it's not.
这只是你财产的九牛一毛
It's a drop in the bucket from your estate.
你说你想参加是因为你对这次竞选有信心
You said you wanted in because you believed in this campaign.
-没错  -现在看来你是为了钱
- That's right. - Sounds like it's more about money.
我希望被重视  25万和少量广告投入并不多
It's about being valued. Two-fifty and the points is a bargain.
我想为你工作  而不是向你乞讨
I want to work for you, just not as a beggar.
我们还不信任你  道格
We don't trust you yet, Doug.
可以说根本不信任你  所以你就是在乞讨
We don't even halfway trust you, so you are a beggar.
我还没证明自己  你也不应该信任我
And you shouldn't trust me... until I prove myself.
你不拿出筹码
That's a gamble you don't get to take
就不能冒这个险
without putting chips on the table.
我和会辛西娅谈的
Cynthia and I will discuss.
感谢你抽空
Thank you for your time.
我先看下外面
Let me check first.
好了  安全
Okay, it's clear.
-你怎么看  -为什么要冒险
- What do you think? - Why take the gamble?
我不想一开始决策
I don't want us to start making decisions
就处于劣势  只会吃亏
from a position of weakness. That is how you lose.
我觉得这是引狼入室
I think we're inviting the fox into the hen house.
要是间谍会
Anyone who wants to be a mole
毫不犹豫地接受条件
accepts the first offer without question.
他却讨价还价
He's negotiating.
所以你相信他了
So you actually believe him?
半信半疑
Not necessarily.
但这不代表他没有价值
But that doesn't mean that he doesn't have value.
这些我们不需要了
Yeah, we're not gonna need any of these.
全都放在这里
We're gonna keep these right here.
凯特·鲍德温  久仰久仰
Kate Baldwin, the one and only.
我就说听到这里有人
I thought I heard somebody in here.
欢迎来白宫  或者应该说欢迎回白宫
Welcome to the White House. Or welcome back, I should say.
这里比我记忆中小
It feels smaller than I remember.
-他们安排你坐哪里  -这里  第二排
- Where do they have you sitting? - Right there, second row.
我以为你会想要第一排
I would've thought you wanted first row.
我听说你说话会飞吐沫
I heard you spit when you talk.
明天总统会讲什么
What's the president speaking about tomorrow?
-你真是不浪费一分一秒  -没错
- You don't waste a minute, do you? - No.
实不相瞒  我很惊讶
I gotta say, I was surprised
《电讯报》会派你来采访白宫
that the Telegraph sent you to cover the White House.
谁会离开伦敦分社啊
I mean, who leaves the London bureau?
艾拉是我的爱徒
Ayla was a protégée of mine.
明白了  他们把老师父都请来了
I see, so now they bring in the big guns.
就一位师父  资历也够老
Just one gun, but big enough.
-别打我的主意  -什么主意
- Don't get any ideas. - About what?
这个记者证我不会摘的
This is gonna stay around my neck.
你不能连续解雇两个《电讯报》的记者
You can't boot two reporters in a row from the Telegraph.
-更不能是两个女记者  -我没这个意思
- Certainly not two women. - I have no desire to do that.
跟你合作  我很荣幸
It's an honor to work with you.
普利策奖  皮博迪奖
Pulitzer, Peabody.
再拿个诺贝尔奖  就是三料冠军了
Get yourself a Nobel, you'll have a trifecta.
你可真会说话
Oh, you're almost charming.
凯特  我不是你的敌人
Kate, I'm not your enemy here.
艾拉没做错  你却惩罚她
You punished Ayla for doing good work.
她发力  你反击  很公平
She hit hard and you hit back. Fair enough.
我会加倍发力
Well, I'm gonna hit twice as hard as she ever did
因为我可以  也应该这么做
because I can and because someone should.
放马过来吧
I look forward to it.
你真不会说谎  我们明早见
You're such a terrible liar. I'll see you bright and early.
有时间吗
You got a minute?
有
Sure.
这是明天声明的草稿
Here's the draft for the statement tomorrow.
想让你斧正一下
I want it to be perfect.
国会肯定会火力全开  回击我们
Congress will fire back, all guns blazing,
邓巴也肯定会大作文章
and I'm sure Dunbar will make a meal and a half out of it.
但我觉得准备进攻的感觉很好
But I gotta say, I feel good. To be on the offensive.
如果不能私下东拼西凑出这些钱来
If I can't scrape the money together behind the scenes,
我就光天化日之下抢银行
I'll rob the bank in broad goddamn daylight.
我们要强行逼迫他们通过《美国就业法案》
We'll cram America Works down their throats and watch them choke.
不再谨小慎微
Enough tiptoeing.
给
Here.
这些改动很棒
Oh, these changes are good.
看你这么兴奋  我也很高兴
It makes me happy to see you excited.
我又能松口气了
I feel free again.
-真希望我也能  -还在忙决议案吗
- I wish I felt the same. - The resolution?
还有些最后的安抚工作  但...
Just some last minute hand-holding, but...
我相信我们会成功的
I think we'll get there.
我完全相信你
I have complete confidence in you.
-你喜欢这个房间吗  -还不错
- Do you like this room? - It's fine.
我还没在这儿过过夜呢
You know, I haven't spent the night here yet.
-也许我可以...  -我明早七点飞机
- Maybe I could-- - My plane leaves at seven.
我得睡一会儿
I should probably get some sleep.
明天记得看新闻  会很有意思的
You watch the news tomorrow. Should be fun.
-我会的  -晚安
- I will. - Good night.
17年  我在警局工作17年
Seventeen years, I served the Metro Police.
我见过杀人抢劫
I've seen robberies and murders.
见过毒品的瘟疫
I've seen the blight of drugs.
我见过小孩子
I've seen little kids
每天只能吃到从学校领到的那一顿饭
whose only meal each day was the one they get at school.
知道这些事的根源是什么吗
You know what's at the root of all that?
因为人们没有工作
Folks don't have jobs!
华盛顿有六万失业人口
There are 60,000 unemployed people in Washington.
这是场灾难
It's a disaster.
更丢脸的是  这是国家的首都
And it's a disgrace here in the nation's capital.
所以今早  在总统的敦促下
So this morning, at the president's urging,
我宣布哥伦比亚特区进入紧急状态
I am declaring a state of emergency in the District of Columbia.
并正式申请从联邦应急管理署赈灾基金
And I am formally requesting three billion dollars
拨款30亿  用以安排人们重回岗位
from FEMA's Disaster Relief Fund to put people back to work.
混帐东西
Motherfucker.
任何人  真的是任何人
Anyone, and I mean anyone,
只要在哥伦比亚特区注册求职
who registers for work in the District of Columbia
就保证可以得到工作
will be guaranteed a job.
我在跟内阁努力增加
I'm working with my cabinet to increase
基础设施建设  保养和修理方面的岗位
workforce devoted to infrastructure, maintenance and repair.
国防部
The Defense Department
会增加探员招募和文职人员招聘
will ramp up recruitment and civilian employment.
任何雇佣《美就法》注册人员的私营企业
And any private sector companies who hire AmWorks registrants
将得到每个岗位每年最高
will get up to $45,000 toward the yearly salary
4.5万美元的薪水补贴
of each job that they create.
我们的目标是12个月内全员就业
Our goal is full employment within twelve months.
我们希望华盛顿的成功
Our hope is that success in Washington
能说服国会在全国供资支持《美国就业法案》
will convince Congress to fund America Works nationwide.
现在  我会回答几个问题
Now, I'll take a few questions.
总统先生
Mr. President!
大使女士  借一步说话
Madam Ambassador. A word, please.
失陪
Excuse me.
我们要收回对维和决议案的支持
We are withdrawing support of the peacekeeping resolution.
-为什么  -因为以色列要收回
- Why? - Because Israel is.
巴勒斯坦愿意接受计划  但不达成共识...
Palestine is open to the plan, but without consensus...
这是直接来自耶路撒冷的意思吗
This came directly from Jerusalem?
-是的  外交部长  -伊莉安娜说什么了吗
- Yes, the foreign minister. - Nothing came from Eliana?
没有  但我是来找她谈的
No, but I came to speak to her.
我会亲自跟她谈  谢谢你  哈桑
I'll speak to her myself. Thank you, Hasan.
谢谢你  大使
Thank you, Ambassador.
莫斯科威胁说要卖武器给伊朗
Moscow is threatening to sell arms to Iran.
他们时常这么威胁
They always make that threat.
耶路撒冷方面认为这个决议案
The feeling in Jerusalem is that this resolution
也许会逼他们铤而走险  不值得冒险
may push them over the edge. It's not worth the risk.
你为什么不来找我  还有两小时就要投票了
Why didn't you come to me? The vote's in two hours.
我30分钟前刚接到电话
I got the call 30 minutes ago.
俄罗斯不想丢面子
Russia doesn't want to be humiliated
因为我们绕过了他们
because we did this without them.
你知道他们就是虚张声势
You know it's a bluff on their part.
总理认为这次投票只是象征性的
The prime minister feels that this vote is just symbolic.
美国不会真的出动军队
That the US won't actually contribute troops.
不  一旦通过  我们绝对会坚持到底
No, we will absolutely follow through once it's passed.
总理有疑虑
The prime minister has his doubts.
抱歉  这不是我能控制的
I'm sorry, it's out of my hands.
克莱尔
Claire?
各位大使  我需要你们撤回决议案
Ambassadors, I need you to withdraw the resolution.
我们不能达成共识
We lost consensus.
我需要推迟投票  直到我们重新达成共识
I need to postpone the vote until we get it back.
特拉弗斯部长是个很好的例子
Secretary Travers is a good example.
国土安全部
Homeland Security?
-应该说是前部长  -他下台了吗
- Former secretary, I should say. - He's done?
还没宣布  但史蒂夫打电话给我了
They haven't announced, but Steve called me.
说他在联邦应急管理署的事上反对总统
Said he stood up to the president on this FEMA nonsense.
国土安全部对联邦应急管理署有管辖权
Homeland Security has jurisdiction over FEMA now.
没错
Right.
总统当场要求他提交辞呈
The president demanded his letter of resignation right then and there.
-这些都是非正式对话  -明白
- This is all off the record. - Yeah.
-保罗真是个大嘴巴  -所以是真的吗
- Paul's got a big mouth. - So it's true?
-这是非正式对话吗  -绝对是
- This is off the record? - Completely.
我用加密电话给你打
Let me call you on my encrypted phone.
我的号码有屏蔽  所以...
My number is blocked, so--
这里是国土安全部  我有你电话
This is Homeland Security. I have your number.
有电话呼入  按接听键...
Incoming call. Press the pickup bu--
-部长先生  -是真的  我辞职了
- Mr. Secretary. - It's true. I resigned.
那你为什么还在办公室
Why are you still in the office?
点卯撞钟等白宫公布
Punching the clock until the White House wants to go public.
如果你反对那项政策
Why wouldn't you go public yourself,
为什么不自己公布消息
if you're so against the policy?
我是为总统服务的
I serve at the pleasure of the president.
兰德里已经提供了信息
I have Landry on background.
我要写关于辞职的报道
I'm writing about the resignation.
我无法阻止你  但你不能引用我的话
And I can't stop you. But there won't be a quote from me.
别让政府逃脱责任
Don't let the administration off the hook.
这是发表反对意见的机会
This an opportunity to speak out.
能做到我这一步
You don't have the career I've had
不是靠公开批评上司
by criticizing your bosses publicly,
不管你觉得自己多厉害
no matter how strongly you feel.
和联邦应急管理署的署长阿尼·希尔瓦谈谈
Talk to Arnie Silva, the FEMA Administrator.
他比我更反感这一切
He's more disgusted by all this than I am.
事关人命  他却不管不顾
People's lives are in the balance. And he doesn't care.
这是我们接下来12个月的预测
Our projections for the next 12 months.
我们正处于拉尼娜时期
We're in a La Niña phase,
也就是说太平洋温度下降
which means falling temperatures in the Pacific.
我们预计这一季至少要发生两次大型山体滑坡
We expect at least two major landfalls this season.
家园被毁  损失数十亿
Homes destroyed, billions in damage,
成千上万人断电
tens of thousands without power.
这还仅仅是飓风的危害  要是碰上大地震
And that's just hurricanes. If we get a major earthquake,
或者洪水  再或森林火灾
or flood, or forest fire...
都在这里面了
It's all in there.
他曾要求你辞职吗
Has he asked you to resign?
他威胁过我
He threatened it.
但是我说我会配合
But I said I'd cooperate.
为什么
Why?
没人比我更有经验
Nobody has more experience.
如果离开  我无法原谅自己
I couldn't forgive myself if I left.
但是你刚才不是说  如果赈灾基金耗尽
But you just said, if the Relief Fund is depleted, then--
那人们会受难
People will suffer.
但在我的照管下  受难的人能少些
But on my watch, fewer will suffer.
我需要引用你的话  希尔瓦先生
I need a quote, Mr. Silva.
我做不到
I can't do that.
人命关天  你有责任
People could die, you have a responsibility.
总统创建了一种噤声与恐惧交织的氛围
The president has built a culture of silence and fear.
你可以结束它
That can end with you.
这个文件夹比任何话语都更有说服力
That folder will speak louder than anything I could say.
同一天头版两篇报道都出自鲍德温女士吗
Two front page bylines on the same day for Ms. Baldwin?
真是踢走只斗狗  放进条火龙来
You kicked out a pit bull and you let in a dragon.
我没想到《电讯报》能再派一个她这样的
I didn't think the Telegraph would send someone like her.
也许你是根本没考虑
Well, maybe you just didn't think.
您让我管束他们  先生
You wanted me to implement discipline, sir.
传递讯息  我做了
To send a message. And so I did.
他们的回应更强烈  是不是
Well, they've sent back an even stronger message, haven't they?
我对此负责  先生
I take responsibility for that, sir,
我会不遗余力让她听话的
and I will do my best to keep her in line.
不遗余力
Your best?
有他们总编辑保着  谁也碰不了她
It's their top bureau chief. She's untouchable.
我不想假装我能百分之百控制她
I don't want to pretend that I can control her 100 percent.
-特拉弗斯  -他否认曾与她谈话
- Travers? - Denied speaking with her,
但是肯定是他
but it must be him.
我想内阁中再没别人会了
I don't think anybody else in the cabinet would.
我们确认他辞职一事
Let's confirm his resignation.
现在还保密没意义了
No point in keeping it a secret now.
告诉史蒂夫他可以把办公室清空了
Tell Steve he can vacate his office.
那希尔瓦呢
And what about Silva?
关于防灾预测的细节相当专业
The details on the disaster projections are very inside baseball.
我们不能炒了他  如果飓风来了
We can't fire him! If there's a hurricane,
他是唯一能防止灾难变成浩劫的人
he's the only guy that can keep a disaster from becoming a catastrophe.
-邓巴说什么  -还没有公开表示
- And what's Dunbar saying? - Nothing yet, publicly.
她可能想让好戏演到终场
She's probably letting this play out.
让我自掘坟墓
Letting me dig my own grave.
我们必须推销《美国就业法案》
We have to sell America Works.
等人们有工作  就不需要别的吹捧了
It should sell itself once we get people employed.
是要这效果  但我们不能止步于此
Well, that's the idea, but we don't stop there.
-广告和公告牌  -用谁的钱
- Commercials and billboards? - On whose money?
即使这样  广告也不够
And even so, we need more than ad-buys.
我们需要...挖掘它背后的深意
We need... We need the philosophy behind it.
我们需要实质性的东西  我们需要...
We need something of substance. We need something...
我们需要能启发想象力的东西
We need something that will capture the imagination.
-你们玩《纪念碑谷》吗  -那是什么
- Either of you play Monument Valley? - What's that?
-是一款游戏  -我不玩游戏  先生
- It's a video game. - I don't play them, sir.
我在易趣上把Xbox卖了  玩着太上瘾
I sold my Xbox on eBay. It was too addictive.
不  不是主机游戏
No, it's not a console game.
你们读读这个
You both read this
然后告诉我你不想玩这个
and then tell me that you wouldn't want to play this.
我敢说全国只有九个顾问
I'd say there's nine consultants in the country
真正懂得外交政策
who truly know foreign policy.
我是第一
Me, I'm number one.
失去意识的我是第二
Me in a coma is number two.
但是还剩下七个逊于我的呢
But that still leaves seven who are cheaper.
我重视良言
I value good counsel,
我也有足够脑子知道自己的欠缺
and I'm smart enough to know what I don't know.
截至目前你对我们的评价如何
What would be your assessment of us so far?
迈克尔·科里根的事你处理得一团糟
You're making a big stink out of this Michael Corrigan thing,
但这还只是表面上的
but that's just surface.
你得明白科里根为何被捕
You have to understand why Corrigan got arrested.
佩特罗夫想迎合传统观念人群
Petrov's appealing to his traditional base.
不  这与约旦河谷有关
No. This is about the Jordan Valley.
我不太明白
I don't follow.
复仇
Retaliation.
这得回溯到几个月前的峰会上
It goes back to the summit a couple of months ago.
这里是约旦河谷
Look, this... is the Jordan Valley.
等一下  我放到大屏幕上去
All right, hold on, I'll make it easier.
这是河谷  在这里
That's the Valley. Right there.
1967年以来一直归以色列
Occupied by Israel since 1967,
一直是与巴勒斯坦达成和平协定的拦路虎
it's been a major roadblock in any peace accord with the Palestinians.
安德伍德派维和部队过去  以色列人走了
Underwood sends peacekeeping troops, the Israelis leave,
-巴勒斯坦人开心了  -没那么简单
- the Palestinians are happy. - It's not that simple.
所有人都为这个小地方牵肠挂肚
Everyone gets hung up on this little patch of land ten miles by 40,
但你得往远了看
but you have to look outwards,
越过约旦  叙利亚还有伊拉克
past Jordan and Syria, past Iraq.
这里  高加索山脉
Here... to the Caucasus.
这里是俄罗斯的地盘
That's Russia's sphere of influence.
他们不觉得维和部队是中东问题
They don't see the peacekeeping force as a Middle East issue.
而是觉得这是美国军队的战略调度
They see it as strategic deployment of US troops
离他们南部边界不到一千里
less than a thousand miles from their southern border.
你是说  科里根只是一枚棋子  一个筹码
So you're saying Corrigan's a pawn, a play for leverage?
更像是打响的第一枪
More of a first salvo.
莫斯科要表明对反抗决议案的决心
Moscow wants to show it's serious about fighting this resolution.
要我猜的话
Now, if I had to guess,
安德伍德在峰会时本想拉拢俄罗斯
Underwood tried to bring Russia into the mix during the summit.
成为合作伙伴
Get involved early on as partners.
但佩特罗夫不肯合作
And when Petrov didn't play ball,
安德伍德就转守为攻  是场豪赌
Underwood went on the offensive, which is a huge gamble.
-怎么说  -没人想让联合国军队过去
- Tell me how. - Nobody wants UN troops there.
以色列人不想  巴勒斯坦人不想
Not the Israelis, not the Palestinians,
阿拉伯人也不想
not the Arabs.
他们合作都是因为美国的施压
They're playing along because the US is pressuring them.
但只要有一点差错
But just one little thing needs to go wrong,
所有人都拿着火柴等着点你的炸药包
and you've got a tinderbox where everyone's holding matches.
那他为什么要采取这样的行动
So why is he following this course of action at all?
因为他很聪明
Because he's smart.
-可你刚说  -他是聪明过头
- You just said-- - He's being too smart.
要是这招行得通  他能拿诺贝尔奖
If it pays off, hey, he wins a Nobel Prize. But...
但行不通的话  他毫无反击之力
if it backfires, he leaves himself wide open.
到时你得火力全开抨击他
And that's when you need to hit him hard.
一项让世界更为危险的灾难性外交政策
A disastrous foreign policy that made the world more dangerous.
他还让他毫无外交经验的妻子
And he had his wife with zero foreign policy experience
-主掌大局  -我想让你加入  乔
- lead the goddamn charge. - I'd like to bring you aboard, Joe.
-你什么时候能开工  -我已经开工了
- When can you start? - I believe I already did.
我今天稍后会把文件给你拿来
I'll get the paperwork over to you later today.
我想问下  是谁推荐的我
Let me ask, who referred me?
-你声名在外  -是啊  声名在外的混蛋
- You have quite a reputation. - Yeah, for being an asshole.
肯定是你尊敬的人大力举荐了我
Somebody you respect must have recommended me highly.
安德伍德的前雇员
A former Underwood staffer.
我没跟他的人共事过
I never worked with any of his people.
这也是他举荐你的原因之一
Which is one of the reasons he recommended you.
有道理
Touché.
这是什么
What is this?
如果你们卖给伊朗一丁点武器
A list of the Russian officials who will be sanctioned
就将遭制裁的俄国官员名单
if you sell a single truckload of arms to Iran.
我都没进前十
I didn't even make the top ten.
制裁会进一步扩大
These sanctions can and will escalate.
然后呢
And then what?
我们联合起来  实现对他们的制裁
We'd build a coalition to impose their own sanctions.
然后呢
And then what?
亚历克西
Alexi,
你明白这会在俄罗斯造成怎样的金融危机
you know what an economic crisis that would be for Russia.
就如你们和中国打的贸易战一样吗
Like the trade war you waged with China?
只不过我们只有3%的出口额是给美国
Except in our case, only three percent of exports go to the US.
欧洲需要我们的天然气
And Europe needs our natural gas.
他们不会为几个给伊朗的短程导弹放弃这些
They won't forfeit that over a few short-range missiles to Iran.
你不会想在恐怖主义国家军备
You don't want to challenge us
这种问题上挑战我们
on the armament of a terrorist state.
我们永远不会出现这种问题
We'll never be presented with that problem.
你无法向以色列人保证出军
You can't assure the Israelis you'll provide troops.
国会两党都不支持总统
The President doesn't have the support of either party in Congress.
不出兵就没有以色列支持
No troops, no Israel.
没有以色列支持就没有共识
No Israel, no consensus.
没有共识  决议案就没戏
No consensus, no resolution.
我会让决议案通过的
I will get this resolution passed.
不要小瞧我的能力和决心
Don't underestimate my ability or desire to do so.
我放任你的热情够久了
I've indulged your enthusiasm long enough.
你有点好高鹜远啊  克莱尔
You've bit off more than you can chew, Claire.
交给专业人士来处理
Leave this to the professionals
你的决议案也能死得痛快点
and let your little resolution die a painless death.
事实就是  你不是当大使的料
The truth is, you have no business being ambassador
就跟我不是当第一夫人的料一样
any more than I do being First Lady.
裙子不错
That's a very nice dress, by the way.
"她用扫帚捅地板
"She stabbed the floor with a broom.
每周三卡拉OK之夜
Karaoke every Wednesday.
会有音痴的醉妞唱毁小甜甜的歌
Some tone-deaf drunk girl mutilating Britney Spears.
她知道楼下酒吧听不到楼上捅扫帚的声音
She knew they couldn't hear the broom in the bar below.
但我们都需要一种形式  而这是她的
But we all need a ritual, and this was hers.
捅三下  木头对木头
Three short thrusts, wood on wood,
完全没有作用的空洞之声
a hollow sound which accomplished nothing.
戴维马上就回家了
David would be home soon.
他会说  '太热了'  她打开了窗户
'It's too hot,' he'd say. She opened the window.
音乐非常大声  她无法忽略"
The music was so loud, she couldn't ignore it."
给你
Here.
你不买新的吗
Aren't you gonna buy the new one?
我会买电子书  但你能在这本上签字吗
I will, on my Kindle. But will you please sign this?
-写给谁  -莱斯莉  LESLEY
- Who should I make it out to? - Lesley. L-E-S-L-E-Y.
《天蝎》改变了我的生活
Scorpio totally changed my life.
那种力量  愤怒  是你的书里我最喜欢的
The energy and the anger... It's my favorite book of yours.
大概是我最喜欢的书了
Probably my favorite book, period.
-一定要读新的  -好的
- Make sure you read the new one. - Yes.
要写给谁呢
Who should I make it out to?
这是对《斯塔福法案》的曲解  你心里清楚
It's a perversion of the Stafford Act and you know it.
这对《斯塔福法案》的解读  我们的解读不同
It's a reading of the Stafford Act. We read it differently.
你不能占用
You can't just raid funds
国会调拨用于特定用途的资金
that Congress appropriated for a specific use,
-任意按你的想法使用  -显然我可以
- then use them however you want. - Clearly, I can.
这是在直接挑衅国会  总统先生
This is a direct challenge to Congress, Mr. President.
鲍勃和我已经同意
Bob and I have agreed.
两党都会在这个问题上反对你
Both parties will fight you on this.
那至少我促进了两党合作
Well, at least I'm cultivating bipartisanship.
先生们  我不想这样做
Gentlemen, I don't want to do this,
但你们给我留了什么选择余地吗
but what choice have you left me?
我们立法部门就是要审核你的行政部门
Our branch is here to check yours.
如果我们认为《美国就业法案》
If we didn't feel America Works
不配使用纳税人的钱
warranted taxpayer money,
-那就不能立法  -听我说
- then it's not fit to be law. - Now, look.
这是两党领导人第一次一起
This is the first time that the leaders of both parties
跟我同处一室会面
have met with me in one room,
而且不是因为我没邀请过你们  是你们拒绝了
and not because I didn't invite you, because you declined.
既然我们都在这里  那就充分利用这次机会
So, now that we're here, let's make the most of it.
我愿意在联邦应急管理署方面让步
I'm willing to walk back on FEMA
前提是让《美就法》进入国会投票
if we can discuss putting AmWorks on the floor.
你们在教育法案上威逼过我们
You bullied us on the Education Bill.
还有政府停摆
And the government freeze.
这次不会成功的
It's not gonna work this time.
等它成功了  你再说这话吧
You watch it work and then tell me it didn't.
我们要起草法律  说这样使用赈灾基金是违法的
We're drafting a law, saying this use of the DRF is illegal.
谁来执行这项法律
And who's going to enforce that law?
我们曾准备弹劾一位总统
We were ready to impeach one president.
如果有必要  也会对你采取相同措施
We'll do the same with you if necessary.
然后让唐纳德·布莱斯坐进这间办公室吗
And put Donald Blythe in this office?
你们也知道他干不了这份工作
You know he's not up for the job.
国会会因为失职而被抨击
Congress would get killed for malpractice.
不管你们认为我多狡诈
As crooked as you may think I am,
你们清楚我可以顶住压力  而唐纳德不行
you know I can handle the pressure, and you know Donald can't.
你们通过法律吧  我会否决的
So pass your law, I'll veto it.
等你们在参议院推翻我
And when you overrule me in the Senate,
我们就让法庭裁决吧
we'll let the third branch decide.
别向国会宣战  总统先生
Don't declare war on Congress, Mr. President.
不是向国会宣战  我是向衰退宣战
Not on Congress. I'm declaring war on atrophy.
但如今谁又能看出区别呢
But these days, who could tell the difference?
不如这样
So how about this?
我叫份披萨
I'll order a pizza.
到了之后  我拿进这个房间
When it gets here, I bring it into this room...
手臂上搭一条纸巾
with a paper towel draped over my arm.
来了  就像客房服务
Voilà. Just like... room service.
你不让你的孩子吃披萨
You don't let your kids eat pizza.
因为我见识过那对颈动脉的危害
Well, because I've seen what it does to a carotid artery.
而且你又不是我的孩子
And you're not my kids.
你觉得他们喜欢我吗
Do you think they like me?
他们崇拜你
They adore you.
马特问你能不能教他开车
Matt asked if you could teach him how to drive.
-真的吗  -嗯
- Really? - Yeah.
他说你不会那么苛刻
He says you'd be less judgmental.
你想结婚吗
Do you want to get married?
跟你还是笼统来说
To you, or in general?
我是认真的
I'm serious.
从哪冒出的想法
So where'd this come from?
我们都谈过了
We've talked about it.
我们说"我爱你"
We say "I love you."
我想要个丈夫  你想要个妻子
I want a husband. You want a wife.
我们俩挺合适  你不觉得吗
This works, the two of us, don't you think?
-非常浪漫  -我们不是浪漫过了吗
- It's very romantic. - Aren't we past romance?
我给你买了个戒指
I bought you a ring.
你为什么都没说
Why didn't you say anything?
不然怎么是惊喜
It's the element of surprise.
不就是要有惊喜吗
That's kind of the point, isn't it?
在我的储物箱里  你想要的话我去拿
It's in my glove compartment. I can go get it if you want.
不  我要你定披萨
No, I want you to order the pizza.
明天再弄戒指的事
We can do the whole ring thing tomorrow.
你什么时候回来的
When did you get in?
-几小时前  -过来坐吧
- Couple of hours ago. - Well, come and sit down.
我觉得我好像有三天没见到你了
I feel like I haven't seen you for what, has it been three days?
应该是四天
Four, I think.
都记不清了
It's just all been a big blur.
我在纽约也一样
Same in New York.
有好消息吗
Any luck?
他们跟复读机似的  弗兰西斯
They're like a broken record, Francis.
需要我给总理打电话吗
Do I need to call the prime minister?
一通电话可能解决不了
Oh, I think it's gonna take more than a phone call.
-说说吧  -其实我不是为这个来的
- Tell me. - That's not why I'm here, actually.
这几个月的事太多
So much has been going on in the past few months,
咱俩都没时间聊聊了
we hardly have time to talk.
用这个
Here, use this.
那晚你要睡我的床
I feel bad about the other night
我不该赶你走
when you wanted to sleep in my bed.
不用自责
Oh, that. You shouldn't.
我就是
I just--
我也不知道为什么在那边睡了
I don't know why I started sleeping in there.
没记错的话是你感冒了
Well, if I remember correctly, you had a cold.
但我为什么没回去
But why I stayed.
你不用解释
You don't have to explain.
我想说我爱你
I want you to know that I love you.
不是因为这个
It has nothing to do with that.
我像以前一样爱你
I love you... as much as ever.
不用说了
Not another word.
明早继续谈以色列的事吧
Let's finish talking about Israel in the morning.
你说一通电话解决不了
You said more than a phone call?
他们需要承诺  弗兰西斯  真会出兵
They need it in stone, Francis, that we'll contribute troops.
-行政命令  -国会肯定不乐意
- An executive order. - Congress won't be happy.
反正已经不开心了
Well, they're already not happy.
恶心了他们一次  就不在乎第二次了
I spat in one eye, I might as well spit in the other.
没问题
Consider it done.
谢谢  谢谢你的支持
Thank you. Thank you for your support.
非常感谢  谢谢
Thank you so much. Thank you.
谢谢  可以啊
Thank you. Oh, sure.
拍到了吗
Did you get it?
谢谢  非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you so much.
谢谢  谢谢你的支持
Thank you. Thank you for your support.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
我喜欢你的演讲  邓巴女士
I liked your speech, Ms. Dunbar.
我听过的演讲可多了
And I've heard more than a few.
非常感谢  先生
I appreciate you saying that, sir.
我知道爱荷华州人不容易取悦
I know Iowans aren't easily impressed.
你之前怎么说正直来着
What you said about integrity?
你要是保证做位正直的总统
Well, if you can bring that to Washington,
我党团会议就支持你
I'll caucus for you.
一次争取一名支持者  选举就得这样
One supporter at a time. That's how we'll win this.
那个小伙子  我替他难过  他令人振奋
And that young man? I feel for him. He's an inspiring individual.
约翰  来见见这位先生
John, there's someone I want you to meet.
-您叫什么  -克莱夫·雷诺兹
- Your name, sir? - Clive Reynolds.
-雷诺兹先生  幸会  -我在为你丈夫祈祷
- Mr. Reynolds, nice to meet you. - I'm praying for your husband.
他还在俄罗斯真是可惜
It's awful he's still stuck there.
谢谢  雷诺兹先生
Thank you, Mr. Reynolds.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
谢谢你们的支持  谢谢你们前来
Thank you for your support. Thank you for coming out.
打个电话就好了
You could've just called.
我讨厌在华盛顿过国庆
I hate July Fourth in DC.
还想看看你怎么拉选票
Plus, I wanted to see you in action.
怎么样
What'd you think?
她得离开
I need her to leave.
车上见
I'll meet you at the car.
-希瑟  -辛西娅
- Heather-- - Cynthia.
看看吧
Read that.
安德伍德夫人要我毁掉
Mrs. Underwood asked me to destroy it.
-我没照做  -应该毁掉的
- I didn't. - You should have.
她在全国电视上说谎了
She lied on national television.
我不会用这种手段竞选的
I am not running that sort of campaign.
至少你知道手里有牌了
But it's good to know it's available.
我绝不会那么对一个女人
I would never do that to another woman,
辛西娅也不会
and neither would Cynthia.
选辛西娅做竞选经理挺不错
Cynthia was a good choice for your manager.
她肯定能经营好团队
She'll run a top-notch operation.
但你需要有人做一些
But you need someone who's willing to do the things
她下不去手的事
that people like her won't do.
你要我聘用你的时候
When you asked me for a job,
你说你想翻开新的一页
you said you wanted to turn over a new leaf.
我的技能很固定  邓巴女士
I have a certain skill set, Ms. Dunbar.
对我来说  翻开新的一页
For me, turning over a new leaf
就是为好目的使用我的技能
is using my skills for the right reasons.
比如帮你当选
Like putting you in office.
15万  广告投入的1%
One-fifty. One point on the ad-buy.
广告投入不行
No points.
但帮我赢得提名
But I'll do a hundred thousand win bonus
给你十万奖金
if we get the nomination.
希望你是有好消息
I hope I came over here for some good news.
我加入  告诉总统吧
I'm in. You can tell the president.
8月19号
August 19th.
我们需要的宣布时间比那早很多
We wanted you to announce a lot earlier than that.
不  不是宣布参选  是这个
No, not the announcement. This.
心脏病医生挺阔啊
Cardiology's good money.
你不恭喜一下吗
Aren't you gonna say congrats?
从没见你这么少女心
I've never seen you be this girly.
这他妈是钻戒啊  少女一下怎么了
It's a fucking diamond. I'm allowed to be a little girly.
恭喜  我为你们俩高兴
Congratulations. I'm happy for you both.
真的吗
Are you?
抱歉  我不该那么说
Sorry. That wasn't fair.
也许我们该谈谈宣布竞选的时间
Maybe we should talk about dates for announcing the campaign.
对  我想到几个时间  让我看下日程表
Yeah, I have a few ideas. Let me pull up my calendar.
下下周似乎最合适
Week after next seems to be the best option.
你今晚有约吗
You have plans tonight?
去看烟火
For the fireworks?
艾伦和我准备带他的孩子一起去
Alan and I are taking his kids.
好吧  也对
Right. Makes sense.
你刚才说下下周吗
You were saying, about a week after next?
-大使在里面  -你要我进去吗
- The Ambassador's inside. - You want me to go in there?
她只是在化妆
She's just putting on makeup.
我可以等她出来
I can wait until she comes out.
她会直接去机场  如果您不介意的话
She's going straight to her plane. If you don't mind.
亚历克西
Alexi.
今天过得太快  我得马上去华盛顿
The day got away from me, so I have to head down to DC
参加国庆庆祝活动
for the July Fourth celebration.
你可以当我是男卫生间的大使
You may consider me an Ambassador from the men's room.
别逗我笑  否则我就得重化
Don't make me laugh. I'll have to start over.
-怎么样  -很美
- Good? - Quite.
亚历克西  我们之前一直有敌意
Alexi, I think we've gotten off on the wrong foot.
我们得找到更好的合作方法
We need to find a better way to work together.
你要撤回决议案吗
You're letting go of the resolution?
-眼妆呢  -堪称完美
- Eyes? - Perfect.
听听男人的看法总是好事
It's always nice to have a man's opinion.
顺便说下  你是对的
You were right, by the way.
只有我们派兵  以色列才会支持我们
Israel won't back us unless we commit troops.
你识破了我的虚张声势  亚历克西
You called my bluff, Alexi,
而我就不该如此  这是侮辱你
and I shouldn't have insulted you with one in the first place.
我去外面等你了
I'll be outside when you finish.
总统今早签署了一份行政命令
The President signed an Executive Order this morning.
五千名美国士兵被派去
Five thousand US military reassigned
长久待命支援联合国维和行动
to permanent standby for UN Peacekeeping operations.
耶路撒冷已知晓此事
Jerusalem has been informed.
你丈夫并没有这种权利
Your husband doesn't have that kind of authority.
那是占领区  他并未向他国领土派兵
It's occupied territory. He's not deploying on sovereign land.
作为三军统帅
So, as Commander in Chief,
他不需要得到国会批准
he doesn't need Congressional approval.
以色列又与我们同一阵线了  亚历克西
Israel's back on board again, Alexi,
只要你们向伊朗出售军火
so the moment you sell arms to Iran,
我们会击落运输机  击翻货运卡车
we will shoot the planes out of the sky, the trucks off the road,
击沉货船
and the ships out of the water.
也许你们不怕遭到制裁
Now... maybe you'd be able to afford sanctions...
但你们绝不敢挑起战争
but you sure as hell can't afford a war.
重新回到谈判桌上来  与我们真诚谈判
Come back to the table. Engage us in good faith.
否则下周决议案就将进入表决环节
Or the resolution goes to a vote next week.
我一直很愿意与你磋商
I have always been willing to talk.
我不是说你与我  是总统间的对话
Not you and I. President to president.
我们还需要你们释放迈克尔·科里根
Oh, and we need Michael Corrigan released, also.
我会将你的意思传达给莫斯科
I'll communicate your message to Moscow.
麻烦了  能给我递张纸巾吗
Please. Hand me a towel, would you?
真有绅士风度
What a gentleman.
你以前来过白宫吗
You ever been to the White House before?
赢得国家图书奖的时候来过
When I won the National Book Award.
-南茜是书迷  -真是出乎我意料
- Nancy was a fan. - I'm surprised.
那个故事可不怎么体现家庭价值观
That story doesn't exactly revere family values.
她流着占星家的血
She's got the astrologer in her.
我觉得她最喜欢的就是标题
I think she liked the title more than anything.
《天蝎》这书很不错
Scorpio was a very good book.
-够糊口而已  -请坐
- Still pays the rent. - Have a seat.
为什么让我来  总统先生
Why am I here, Mr. President?
雷米跟你解释过
Remy briefed you.
他说你需要本书  但没说题材是什么
He said you needed a book. He didn't say about what.
关于《美国就业法案》
America Works.
不只是政策本身  还有它的起源
Not just the policy, but the origins.
一位出身贫寒的少年
How a boy grew up in a dirt-poor shithole
是如何努力工作攀上人生巅峰
and climbed his way out through hard work.
一个关于尊严的故事  努力工作所赢得的骄傲
A story of dignity. The pride that comes with one's labor.
-政治宣传  -也可以这么说
- Propaganda. - You could call it that.
这种文章  我并不擅长
This sort of thing... it's not in my wheelhouse.
您需要推销员  而非小说家
You need a salesman, not a novelist.
"不论你是谁  不论你以为自己是谁
"Whoever you are, whoever you think you are,
想象你是位沉默的公主
believe that you're also a silent princess.
名叫艾达
Your name is Ida.
你的旅程发生在一个被人遗忘的世界
Your journey is one through a forgotten landscape
那里满布了扭曲的阶梯和变形的城堡
of twisting staircases and morphing castles,
你将踩着浮石去征服怒海狂涛
atop floating stones defiantly crossing an angry sea,
探索废墟遍地的昏暗洞穴
within dimly-lit caverns cobwebbed with ruins
荷兰版画家
莫里茨·埃舍尔在梦中才能窥见这样的世界"
M.C. Escher could only grasp at in a dream state."
您读过我写的游戏评测
You read my video game reviews?
我经常玩清版射击游戏
I tend to play shoot-'em-ups.
对独立游戏并不感兴趣
The indie games don't really interest me.
我需要刺激与战斗
I need adrenaline and action.
但当我读了这个  我一定要玩玩看
But when I read this, I had to try it.
如果你仅用一百字
If you can convince me to
就能说服我做一位沉默的公主
be a silent princess with just a hundred words,
想想看你这本书将能说服多少人
imagine how many millions you can convince with this book.
你就是推销员  托马斯
You are a salesman, Thomas.
我没想推销什么  就是讲下我的感受
I wasn't trying to sell anything. Just describe my experience.
我也要你这么对待我的故事
That's exactly what I want you to do with my story.
不要推销  只描述你的探究
No sales pitch, just your honest curiosity.
再说  这种书一般都很无聊  保守
Besides, these kinds of books are always so boring, so safe.
我想要点不同的  独特的
I want something different, something... unique.
你的文笔
Your voice.
我都不知道自己相不相信你的计划
I don't even know if I believe in your program.
跟我来  给你看点东西
Come with me. I want to show you something.
搭起帐篷  大家自然会来
You build it and they come.
均取自电影《梦幻成真》
原片是指建造棒球场
今天的国家广场是梦想之地
Today, the Washington Mall is the real Field of Dreams.
今早开门之后
Three thousand people have registered
来了三千人注册
since we set up shop this morning.
这才叫国庆节聚会
Now that's what I call a Fourth of July party!
这个聚会会不眠不休  一直办下去
And we're gonna keep the party going 'round the clock, 24/7,
直到首都每个想求职的人
till everyone in DC who wants a job
都来这里注册过
can make their way down here and sign up.
看看吧
Have a look.
-看到那队伍了吗  -《美就法》的帐篷
- Do you see that line of people? - The AmWorks tent.
从那儿一直延伸到林肯纪念堂
It stretches from there all the way to the Lincoln Memorial.
天还没亮就开始排队了
They started lining up before sunrise.
真了不起
It's really something.
托马斯  帮不了他们  我成了历史的脚注
Thomas, at best, I'm going to be a footnote in history
那都算好  搞不好还会沦为笑柄
if I can't help those people. At worst, I'll be a joke.
我跟他们一样
I am those people.
我希望你把这个写下来
I want you to tell that story.
怎么样
What do you say?
-不知道  -你的直觉呢
- I don't know. - What's your gut say?
你的话好像不太对劲  但我很感兴趣
That you don't add up, and I'm intrigued.
-但还没说服你  -还没
- But not sold. - Not yet.
钱是肯定不会少了你的
Well, I'll pay you well, and at the very least,
这种活儿一向能捞一笔  是吧
this sort of access is worth its weight in gold, isn't it?
先生  第一夫人回来了
Sir, the First Lady's back.
我得在放焰火之前致辞
I have to go give my Fourth of July speech before the fireworks.
-您要多久写完  -一月之前
- How quickly would you need the book? - By January.
我写东西一向要一年多
I've never written anything in less than a year.
我看你的样子
Well, you don't strike me
不像遇到挑战就会退缩
as someone who shies away from a challenge.
我得按我自己的方式写
I'd need to be able to write it the way I want to write it.
没问题  多待一会儿  看看风景
Absolutely. Look, take your time. Enjoy the view.
看完了密查姆会送你出去
Meechum will show you out when you're done.
我保证  你答应了绝不会后悔
And I promise, if you say yes, you won't regret it.
有水平的作家都不会拒绝好故事
No writer worth his salt can resist a good story,
就像政客总忍不住乱许诺言一样
just as no politician can resist making promises he can't keep.
维克多  受邀前往是我们的荣幸
Viktor, we'd be honored to accept the invitation.
是啊  要谈的事太多了
Yes, I agree, there's much to discuss.
我会叫我的办公室联系克里姆林宫
I'll have my office reach out to the Kremlin.
安排一个都方便的日期
We'll find dates that work for both of us.
谢谢
Thank you.
你该睡了吧  那边都好晚了
Well, you should get some sleep. It's late over there.
晚安
Good night.
表决暂缓
Hold off on the vote?
等谈了再说  不过留着这一手
Until we sit down. But we keep it in our back pocket.
迈克尔·科里根呢
Michael Corrigan?
我们到访的时候释放他
They're going to release him when we visit.
你造就了奇迹
You made a miracle happen.
是我们
We did.
每一位独一无二的公民都影响着未来
...each unique citizen contributes to our future.
能大点声吗
Can you turn that up?
我们的先辈宣布独立时
Our forefathers, when they declared independence,
就理解个体的力量
understood the power of the individual,
自主的价值
the value of self-determination.
他们把我们从暴政中解放出来
They freed us from tyranny.
-他们证明了...  -他就是暴君
- They proved... - He is a tyrant.
不好说  那里那么多人
I don't know, there's a lot of people out there.
他也许做对了
He might be onto something.
下行政命令调派维和部队  他疯了吧
Executive Order for UN troops? He's out of control.
至少他有所行动  沃克什么都没干
At least he's doing something. Walker didn't do shit.
我们弹劾了个哑炮  换了个原子弹
I think we replaced a dud with an atom bomb.
他们的自由是抗争得来的
They had to fight to secure their freedom.
如今我们也要通过抗争保住自由
And now we have to fight to maintain it.
工作的自由
The freedom to work.
体面活着的自由
The freedom to live with dignity.
希望的自由
The freedom to hope.
谢谢你们  天佑美国
Thank you, and God bless the United States of America.
奥巴马上任后最重要的一个法案
是被称为"奥巴马医改"(Obamacare)的《医疗改革法案》
在经过艰苦的谈判后  这个法案被带到参众两院进行投票
按正常程序  法案需要经过至少两轮投票
在投票过程中要进行一些修改
当时奥巴马所属的民主党在参众两院都处于多数党位置
法案通过似乎没有悬念
但在投票开始后  马萨诸塞州一名民主党参议员突然过世
补选上来的是一名共和党议员
这使民主党在参议院失去了绝对多数
奥巴马费尽心血的法案面临夭折的风险
这时  在奥巴马的支持下
众议院议长佩洛西将这个旨在改革医疗政策的法案
定性为"预算法案"  从而避免了这个法案在参议院进行新的投票
"奥巴马医改"靠这个不是很光明正大的办法成为了法律